# YU CAO

# **Computational Linguist**

San Jose, CA

@ gencaetia@gmail.com

pterosdiacos.github.io

in www.linkedin.com/in/yu-cao-pdiacos

# PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

**Linguistics** Specialized in computational linguistics, seman-

tics, syntax, discourse analysis. Strong critical-

thinking and problem-solving skills.

**Computation** 10+ years of experiences in algorithms and data

structure. First Prize in National Olympiad in Informatics in Provinces 2007, China.

## **EXPERIENCES**

# **Applied Researcher**

#### eBay

## 11/2021 - present

San Jose, CA

- Worked at Content, Item and Inventory Understanding Team.
- Built and evaluated models for understanding listing qualities.

## **Ontology Linguist**

## Facebook via PRO Unlimited

**10/2019 10/2019** 

Redmond, WA

- Worked at Assistant Cross-Functional Group.
- Prototyped cross-domain semantic parsing models for question answering.
- Automated inferences in OWL 2 ontology knowledge graphs.

# **Teaching Assistant**

## **Rutgers University**

**(1)** 09/2018 - 08/2020

New Brunswick, NJ

• Courses taught: Intro to Linguistic Theory, Invented Languages.

# Research Assistant

# The Chinese University of Hong Kong

**12/2014 - 07/2015** 

♥ Hong Kong, China

- Worked at Center for Sign Linguistics and Deaf Studies.
- Provided linguistic expertise in developing Chinese grammatical knowledge assessment software.

# **EDUCATION**

## **Rutgers University**

## Ph.D. in Linguistics

**10/2021 10/2021** 

New Brunswick, NJ

The Chinese University of Hong Kong

M.A. in Chinese Linguistics & Language Acquisition

**⋒** 09/2013 − 06/2014

♥ Hong Kong, China

#### Sichuan Normal University

## B.A. in Teaching Chinese as a Second Language

**1** 09/2009 - 06/2013

Chengdu, China

## **PUBLICATIONS**

Plurality and Quantification in Graph Representation of Meaning (○ code)
Doctoral dissertation on arXiv:2112.06448.
Yu Cao.

Advisor: Simon Charlow.

Automated fact-value distinction in court opinions

**European Journal of Law and Economics 2020.** Yu Cao, Daniel Chen & Elliot Ash. Automated classification of fact vs. value statements in written judicial decisions.

 Investigating BERT's knowledge of language: Five analysis methods with NPIs Proceedings of EMNLP 2019.

Alex W., Yu Cao & 14 others.

Supervisor: Sam Bowman.

Role: constructed and conducted the main transfer learning experiments.

# **SKILLS**

## **Technical**

- Machine learning algorithms, NLP/NLU
- Python, C, Scikit-learn, PyTorch, Tensorflow
- Linguistic analysis, symbolic logic, statistics

#### ML/NLP Coursework

Machine learning

**1** 07/2020

**m** Stanford@Coursera

Seminar: Linguistic knowledge in reusable sentence encoders

**1** 05/2019

<u>m</u> nyu

#### Languages

ENG (fluent) CHN (native) JPN (JLPT N1)